Guide to the Diego Cortez No Wave Collection, circa 1972-1981.
Cortez, Diego No Wave Collection,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Diego Cortez No Wave Collection, circa 1972-1981.
8120
Diego, Cortez
Circa 1.5 cubic feet.
Photographs, artwork, correspondence, manuscripts, and printed material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Approximately 135 pieces complied by Diego Cortez comprising of material related to both his 1981 No Wave show at PS1 and many of the personalities involved in the artistic and musical scenes of the period, including Jimmy DeSana, James Chance, Anya Phillips, Fab 5 Freddy, Bob Gruen, Robert Gordon, Glenn O'Brien, Legs O'Neil, Ray Johnson, Debbie Harry, and Jean-Michel Basquiat, among others. The collection also contains concert flyers, photographs, and exhibition materials, including early proposals for a book and exhibition on graffiti art.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Born James Allen Curtis in Geneva, Illinois in 1946, Curtis moved to New York City in 1973 and assumed the name Diego Cortez. He became well-known as an artist, club manager, promoter, and independent curator, co-founding the influential NYC nightspot The Mudd Club, which offered an eclectic mix of art, music and cultural events that combined both modernist and punk aesthetics. In 1981, Cortez curated the groundbreaking exhibition "New York, No Wave" at a defunct elementary school in Long Island City, Queens called P.S. 1. The exhibition featured the work of David Byrne, Keith Haring, Robert Mapplethorpe, Jean-Michel Basquiat, and Kenny Scharf, among many others.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Approximately 135 pieces complied by Diego Cortez comprising of material related to both his 1981 No Wave show at PS1 and many of the personalities involved in the artistic and musical scenes of the period, including Jimmy DeSana, James Chance, Anya Phillips, Fab 5 Freddy, Bob Gruen, Robert Gordon, Glenn O'Brien, Legs O'Neil, Ray Johnson, Debbie Harry, and Jean-Michel Basquiat, among others. The collection also contains concert flyers, photographs, and exhibition materials, including early proposals for a book and exhibition on graffiti art.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cortez, Diego,; De Sana, Jimmy.
Subjects:
Avant garde.; Avant-garde (Aesthetics) -- New York.; Avant-garde (Aesthetics) -- New York; Avant-garde (Music).; Graffiti.; Graffiti artists.; Nightclubs.; Nightlife.; No wave (Music).; Punk culture.; Punk rock music.
Places:
New York (N.Y.).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence
Series II. Exhibitions
Series III. Manuscripts
Series IV. Periodicals/press materials
Series V. Photographs
Series VI. Posters and flyers
Series VII. Recordings and artwork
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence
  - Letter by Marina Abramovic to Diego Cortez, Abramovic, Marina; Typed letter with signature and flower drawing in ink, written from Belgrade, Yugoslavia. Marina invites Cortez to participate in 'April Meeting' performance festival in Belgrade. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Handwritten letter from Jimmy DeSana to Diego Cortez, 1975; Red ink on paper, signed by DeSana with artist's stamp of camera/hands at top. With envelope with 'CORTEZ' handwritten on it. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Postcard to Diego and Jim DeSana from "cf" (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter by Liz Rhodes to Diego Cortez, Two-sided handwritten letter with signature, written from London, with notations by Cortez. At the behest of Peter Gidal, Rhodes invites Cortez to show films at the London Film Cooperative. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter to DC from Udo Breger, One page letter with attached photograph of Breger. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    DC met Breger through William S. Burroughs. Breger was the editor of the Swiss Journal SOFT NEED.
    Bonn, Germany
  - Letter to DC c/o Betsy Sussler from Udo Breger, Two small pages, one with attached photo of Breger. In postmarked envelope. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Gotteborg, Germany
  - Letter by Peter Gidal to "Hernando Cortez", Signed. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Experimental filmmaker Peter Gidal also head of London Filmmakers Cooperative. Aerogramme letter by Gidal from London re: possible film screenings by DC in London.
  - Letter by Norman Rosenthal to Diego Cortez, Two-sided handwritten letter by Rosenthal from London. Signature on verso. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    He sums up the state of affairs at the I.C.A. and other venues in London.
  - Letter from Pasquale Trisorio to Diego (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Postcard from Marek Konieczny, Warsaw, Signed by Makarewicz. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Re: film screening at Galeria Wspolszesna
  - Letter by Zbigniew Makarewicz to Consulate General of Poland to the US (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Requesting artistic visa for Cortez re: a film screening in Warsaw.
  - Letter by Makarewicz to Cortez (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Re: film screening at Galeria Wspolszensna, Warsaw
  - Typed letter by Diego Cortez to Candida Höffer (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Re: Cortez's upcoming 'SMEAR' exhibition at Konrad Fischer Gallery, Dusseldorf.
  - Letter by Diego Cortez to Robin Winters, Two-sided typed letter with handwritten notations in ink, written from Germany. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Cortez brings Winters up to date on several European projects.
  - Postcard from Ingrid Oppenheim to DC, Oppenheim, Ingrid (Box 1, Folder 1)
    "Greetings from Ingrid Oppenheim [Koln gallerist]." DC met Oppenheim through Dennis Oppenheim, for whom DC first worked for in NYC in 1973-74.
    Cologne, Germany
  - Letter from DeSana to DC, DeSana, Jimmy; Handwritten. In handwritten envelope "Por Diego Cortez." (Box 1, Folder 1)
    DeSana brings DC up to date on all recent affairs, including the fact that DC ex-roommate Jane Kaplowitz will now move in with historian Robert Rosenblum. DeSana and DC always referred to each other as 'Doctor' and here refers to Jane as 'Nurse.' Also gossip about art critics David Bourdon and Gregory Battcock.
  - Postcard from UK to Diego Cortez, Phillips, Anya (Box 1, Folder 1)
    New York, New York
  - Mailgram (Box 1, Folder 1)
    From Michael Zilkha and Michel Esteban to Cortez, Ze Records.
  - Fab Five Freddy, Offset on card stock. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Calling card.
  - Draft of a letter to Yossy Aoren, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Regarding possible show in Israel.
- Exhibitions
  - Xerox and Blood
    - MoMA security guard notes for 1975 'Xerox and Blood' exhibition, Cortez, Diego; Photograph contact sheet, notebook pages, handwritten in ink, typed letter from Head of MoMA security on MoMA stationary, bank deposit slip, MoMA check stub, note card, etc.
      Cortez was employed as a security guard at MoMA in 1974-75. He was invited to make a show at the Whitney Museum Art Resources Center. The exhibition was titled 'Xerox and Blood' and opened in Spring, 1975. Cortez's made several conceptual wall series which dealt with the issues of security and art. One series reflects on the attack on Picasso's Guernica by artist Tony Shafrazi.
    - Manila envelope, Hand-titled by Cortez. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Images taken at MoMA security office, One photo contact sheet, including arrest pictures of Tony Shafrazi. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Gelatin silver prints
    - MoMA security work ephemera, 30 assorted handwritten-in-ink notebook pages from MoMA security work for Whitney Downtown Museum exhibition by Cortez (most written on both sides); one check stub, one deposit slip, one letter on MoMA letterhead from Head of Security Dept. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Works from 1975 Whitney Downtown Museum show, Cortez, Diego; 75 Xerox works. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Announcements for 1975 "Xerox and Blood" show at Whitney Downtown Museum, Cortez, Diego; 110 Xerox announcements. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Installation plan for 1975 Whitney Downtown Museum show, Cortez, Diego (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Installation plan.
  - Cataratta Riflesso Rosso
    - Notes for photo series 'Cataratta Riflesso Rosso' for 1976 Galleria Trisorio exhibition, Blue ink on paper. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Napoli, Italy
    - Sketches for wall paintings for 1976 'Cataratta Riflesso Rosso' exhibition, Galleria Trisorio, Cortez, Diego; Red and blue inks on found letterhead. Nine pages. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Sketches, notes re: medical photo works in "Cataratta Riflesso Rosso" (Folder 6)
      Exhibition at Studio Pasquale Trisorio
    - Prints documenting Cortez's gallery exhibition 'Cataratta Riflesso Rosso' at Galleria Trisorio, del Monaco, Bruno; Contact prints. Both stamped by del Monaco on verso and numbered by pencil. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Smear, The Batman Show, and Hospital Colors
    - Kodachrome slides, Cortez, Diego (Box 1, Folder 2)
      3 original slides used in Cortez's lecture/performance 'Hospital Colors' performed at 'April Meeting' in Belgrade (1975) and Artists Space, NYC (1976). The lecture analyzed the chromatics of institutional interiors.
    - Study for announcement card for Diego Cortez "SMEAR" exhibition, Cortez, Diego; Color Xerox. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Galerie Konrad Fischer.
      Dusseldorf, Germany
    - Two-sided handwritten note by Diego Cortez (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Note is earliest formulation of the future 1981 'New York/New Wave' show at PS1. Ink and typed text on paper card.
    - Notes for "The Batman Show", Cortez, Diego (Box 1, Folder 7)
      This was the first exhibition which Cortez curated as well as the first exhibition sponsored by Collaborative Projects (COLAB). The exhibition took place at Robin Winters loft in Soho. These are the only notes documenting the organization of that show. Xerox. Signed.
    - Batman's Left Nipple, Johnson, Ray; Collage, mirror mounted on red construction paper. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Johnson's submission to Cortez's 1977 exhibition 'The Batman Show', sponsored by Collaborative Projects (Colab), held at Robin Winters' Soho loft in 1977. Hand printed title and artist's stamp on face of work.
  - New York/New Wave
    - Initial List of Artists, "New York/New Wave" exhibition (1981), Cortez, Diego; Typed list of artists, 6 pages. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Rene Ricard, Armstrong, David; Signed and titled with notations on verso (handwritten specs as to larger print to be made for 'New York/New Wave show, dated '1980'). (Box 1, Folder 9)
      From the New York/New Wave exhibition
    - Untitled (New York/New Wave), Maripol (Box 1, Folder 28)
      2 unique hand-colored Polaroids. These two photographs were exhibited in Cortez's 1981 'New York/New Wave' exhibition at P.S.1.
      diffusion transfer prints
  - Graffiti
    - Remarks on Graffiti (Unpublished), Smith, Duncan; Photocopy with hand-written edits and notations by Cortez. 13 pages. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Graffiti 1980, America's Underground Art Come of Age, Subterranean Calligraphy, 1981 | From Steel to Canvas, The Graffiti 1980 Experience, Zoo York Magazine, 1980, Van Daal, Vincent; Two typewritten manuscripts on Graffiti. 10 pages. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Graffiti Exhibition Proposal, Cortez, Diego; Blue envelope with hand-written title by Cortez. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Berlin, Germany
      Rome, Italy
    - Original Proposal Notes for Unrealized Graffiti Exhibition Project, Spring, Cortez, Diego; Six typed pages. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Screenings
    - Notes for screenings in European cinematheque tour by Cortez, Cortez, Diego; 7-paged handwritten notes. (Box 1, Folder 11)
      At the behest of Jonas Mekas and P. Adams Sitney, Cortez made a tour of European cinematheques and showed a series of films made for the analytic projector which converts a film screening into a 'film performance'. Red ink and black marker on found letterhead with visual diagrams of stills from films
    - Notes for screenings in European cinematheque tour by Cortez, Cortez, Diego (Box 1, Folder 11)
      At the behest of Jonas Mekas and P. Adams Sitney, Cortez made a tour of European cinematheques and showed a series of films made for the analytic projector which converts a film screening into a 'film performance'. Red ink and black marker on found letterhead with visual diagrams of stills from films.
    - Notes on Musée du Cinéma, Cortez, Diego; One-page typed notes on Brussels letterhead (Box 1, Folder 11)
      re: DC 1975-76 European and US tour of exhibitions, performances and film screenings (not all realized).
    - Bio and Notes on Screening for Candida Hoffer, 2-paged xerox. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Notes for "Poisoning", Cortez, Diego (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Including cues. Analytic projector film to be screened in US and Europe. Two pages, Xerox with handwritten notes.
    - Notes re: possible programming of films by Diego Cortez, Cortez, Diego; 5 pgs. typewritten (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Notes on analytic projector specifications and DC biography. Stadtmuseum.
      Munchen, Germany
    - Notes re: "New American Performance" proposal for Stadtische Kunsthalle, Cortez, Diego (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Manuscripts
  - APO-33 Bulletin, A Metabolic Regulator, Burroughs, William S.; Signed by DC on page 1. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Beach Books, Distributed by City Lights
    San Francisco, California
  - Notes for "Cansearch Report", Cortez, Diego (Box 1, Folder 12)
    These notes were made for an unrealized artist book commissioned by Mario Diacono, Bologna. 4 typewritten pages with handwritten notes in ink and pencil.
  - Storyboads for William S. Burroughs film project, Blade Runner, Cortez, Diego (Box 4)
    Extracts from Burroughs' text with notations and collage elements by Cortez, mounted on drawing paper pad. In 1979, Cortez asked Burroughs and his assistant, James Grauerholz, for the film rights for the book and was granted permission. The film was never realized. Burroughs' book is a sci-fi novella which began as a story treatment for a proposed film adaptation of Alan E. Nourse's novel 'The Bladerunner.' Burroughs' treatment has been described as a closet screenplay. It is set in the early 21st century and involves mutated viruses and a medical-care apocalypse. The term 'blade runner' refers to a smuggler of medical supplies, e.g. scalpels. No film was ever made from Burroughs' text. The title was later bought by Ridley Scott for use in his 1982 science fiction film, 'Blade Runner.' Its plot was based on Philip K. Dick's 'Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep?' and not the Nourse/ Burroughs material, although the dialogue incorporates the term 'blade runner' into dialogue.
- Periodicals and press materials
  - Art Rite, Issue No. Ten, Fall (Box 1, Folder 13)
    With participation of Diego Cortez ('Notes on Painter/Patient Performance') and other artists. Joseph Beuys on cover.
  - Art Rite, Issue No. Ten, Fall, Single page of Cortez's 'Notes on Painter/Patient Performance' (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Art Rite, Issue No. 11-12, Winter/Spring, Edward Ruscha on cover. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Anderson, Laurie, Patti Smith, A.A. Bronson, and Lucy Lippard
  - File Magazine, "New York City" Edition, Spring (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Contributions by Cortez.
    Bronson, AA, Feliz Partz, and Jorge Zontal
    General Idea
    Toronto, Canada
  - Announcement re: publication of books by Hermann Nitsch, Offset on cards. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Studio Morra.
  - File Magazine, "Special People Issue" Edition, Spring (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - File Magazine, "Punk 'Til You Puke" Edition, Fall (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Cortez, Diego, Anya Phillips, and Jimmy DeSana
  - Protokolle der Gerfangenen aus der RAF sun Uberfall in Stammheim, Typed list of artists, 10 pages. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    In German
  - MOVED catalogue, Collaborative Projects (COLAB), Typed list of artists, 10 pages. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - New York/New Wave exhibition catalogues, P.S. 1, Offset fold-out, 4 pages. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Long Island City, New York, New York
- Photographs
  - Photo booth auto-portrait, Cortez, Diego; Two variant images on one strip photograph. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Made while Cortez was in MFA program at the School of the Art institute of Chicago. Kodak photo paper. Stmaped and titled by DC on verso.
  - Nam June Paik, DeSana, Jimmy; Unsigned (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Gift of artist to Diego Cortez. This photo was taken at Charlotte Moorman's Avant Garde Festival at Grand Central Station.
  - Chuck Berry, Gruen, Bob; Artist's stamp and date on verso. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Byron Reed, DeSana, Jimmy (Box 1, Folder 15)
    "101 Nudes" model.
    Atlanta, Georgia
  - Photograph of Bobby Daren with Marie Keller (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Marie Keller would later married Duchamp scholar, Francis M. Naumann. Keller, Naumann and DC were close friends while studying at the School of the Art Institute of Chicago (1971-73).
    C-prints
  - Untitled (Self-portrait as airman), DeSana, Jimmy (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Edit DeAk, Diego Cortez, Expression (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Unknown photographer.
  - James Nares, Diego Cortez, East Village, 1976; Tillett, Seth (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Gioia Meller-Marcovicz, Diego Cortez, Stanton St., 1976; Tillett, Seth (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Auto-portrait with dog, 1976; Konieczny, Marek (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Konieczny was a Polish artist who invited DC to Warsaw to show his experimental films in 1976. Vintage silver print, stamped by artist on verso.
    Warsaw, Poland
  - Joseph Beuys, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Untitled (Self-portrait w/ flash), 1977; DeSana, Jimmy (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Diego Cortez, 1977; DeSana, Jimmy; Stamped by artist's stamp on verso. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Judy Nylon, 1977; Phillips, Anya (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Unique Polaroid photograph
  - James Chance, 1977; Phillips, Anya (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Hal Ludiger, 1977; Phillips, Anya (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - James Chance, Anya Phillips, 1977; Phillips, Anya (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Debbie Harry, Anya Phillips, San Francisco boarding house, 1977-04-12; Phillips, Anya (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Diego Cortez, 1977; Vogl, Harald (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Anya Phillips, 1977; Cortez, Diego (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - New Cinema Group, 1977; Godlis, David; Offset newspaper print. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Jimmy DeSana, Mercer St. Loft, Soho, 1977; Cortez, Diego; Hand notated by Cortez on verso. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Katharina Sieverding, Diego Cortez, 1977; DeSana, Jimmy; Artist's stamp on verso. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    For Image Bank Postcard Show, Vancouver.
  - Robert Stefanotty, Jimmy DeSana, Gregory Battcock aboard the Queen Elizabeth 2, 1977; In Cunard Lines matte. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Cunard Lines photograph.
    C-print
  - James Chance, 1977; DeSana, Jimmy (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Diego Cortez as Elvis Presley in 'Grutzi Elvis' film, 1977; Meller-Marcovic, Digne; Artist's stamp on verso. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Darmstadt, Germany
  - Untitled (Self-portrait w/ graduation cap), 1978; DeSana, Jimmy (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Untitled (Self-portrait w/ Spanish hat), 1978; DeSana, Jimmy (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bob Gruen, 1978; DeSana, Jimmy; Artist's stamp on verso. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Diego Cortez, Odeon, NYC, 1978; Grossman, Bobby (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Anya Phillips, James Chance, 1978; DeSana, Jimmy; Artist's stamp on verso. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Billy Idol, 1978; DeSana, Jimmy; Artist's stamp on verso. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Robert Gordon, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Unknown photographer (possibly David Godlis).
  - Diego Cortez (Esoterrorists), 1978; Phillips, Anya (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Gift of artist to Diego Cortez. The 'Esoterrorists' were an imaginary NYC punk band consisting of Anya Phillips, Duncan Smith and Diego Cortez). They only existed as documented by various photos and published in art and music magazines and zines in 1978-79.
  - Esoterrorists, 1978; Vogl, Harald; Unsigned. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Gift of artist to Diego Cortez. This incarnation of the 'Esoterrorists' was as an imaginary Munich punk band consisting of Anya Phillips, Charlie Heil, Harald Vogl and Diego Cortez. These photos by Vogl remain unpublished.
    Munich, Germany
  - Andy Warhol, Diego Cortez and others, 1978; Grossman, Bobby (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Andy Warhol, Diego Cortez, 1978; Grossman, Bobby (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Anya Phillips, Tim Guest, Diego Cortez, 1978; Grossman, Bobby (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Brian Eno, 1978; DeSana, Jimmy (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Diego Cortez, 1978; DeSana, Jimmy (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Boris Policeband, Diego Cortez, 1979; Starr, Michael; Signed and titled on verso. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Washington Square Park
  - Untitled (Self-portrait), 1979; DeSana, Jimmy (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Untitled, 1980; Gruen, Bob; Stamped with artist's stamp and hand-notated as to series. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Gift of artist to Diego Cortez. Taken by Gruen at the Club Fez, in the East Village at a poetry reading in which all the subjects pictured read.
    Bockris, Victor
    Ross, David
    Lindsay, Arto
  - Untitled (Modena, Italy), 1981; Basquiat, Jean-Michel; Unsigned and mounted in window matte. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Six vintage Polaroids. Gift of artist to Diego Cortez. Cortez organized Basquiat's first solo gallery exhibition at Galleria Emilio Mazzoli, which opened May, 1981. Cortez accompanied Basquiat to Modena and installed the show. These were part of about 20 Polaroids Basquiat took in Modena's Piazza Grande during the installation period.
    Modena, Italy
  - Photo booth portrait, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Untitled, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Man standing in front of a storefront
  - Untitled, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Woman and child
  - Diego Cortez, Undated; Handwritten note on verso (Box 1, Folder 18)
    2 photos
  - FILE Magazine
    - A.A. Bronson, Boris Policeband, 1976; DeSana, Jimmy; Handwritten notes by DC on verso. (Box 1, Folder 19)
      For FILE Magazine's NYC issue.
    - Holly Woodlawn, 1976; DeSana, Jimmy; Handwritten notes by DC on verso. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - A.A. Bronson, Holly Woodlawn, 1976; DeSana, Jimmy; Handwritten notes by DC on verso. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Andy Warhol at Factory, 1976; DeSana, Jimmy; Handwritten notes by DC on verso. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Documentation of Performance Piece
    - Autonomia-Post Political Politics, Semiotext(e), 1977; Cortez, Diego; 31 photographs with printers' notations (used in "Autonomia" issue co-edited and designed by Cortez), various sizes. (Box 3)
      Photographers include: Digne Meller Marcovicz, Cortez and others. Original envelope with hand notation by Cortez.
    - P.S.1 Performance, 1979; DeSana, Jimmy; Credit to DeSana handwritten by DC on verso (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Cortez, Diego
      McClard, Michael
      Winters, Robin
    - Diego Cortez, PS1, 1979; Kahane, Lisa; Artist's stamp on verso. (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Documentation of performance piece.
    - Diego Cortez, PS1, 1979; Kahane, Lisa; Artist's stamp on verso. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Diego Cortez, PS1, 1979; DeSana, Jimmy; Artist's stamp on verso. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Diego Cortez, PS1, 1979; DeSana, Jimmy; Artist's stamp on verso. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Diego Cortez, PS1, 1979; Kahane, Lisa; Artist's stamp on verso. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Diego Cortez, PS1, 1980; DeSana, Jimmy; Artist's stamp on verso. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Posters and flyers
  - First Buddha University Meeting for Mary Josephson, 1973-06-09; Johnson, Ray; Xerox handout for performance at Paula Cooper Gallery. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - FILMS poster, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Films by DC and others. ICC International Kulturel Centrum.
    Antwerp, Germany
  - La Conversation Surprise, 1976; Boltanski, Christian; B/W offset foldout for performance at AQ Nr. 12 Theater, Frankfurt. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Talking Heads, Village Gate, 1977; Flier. Offset print on paper. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Tues. Night, 1977-09-27; Asher, Dan; Punk zine poster. Xerox. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - CBGB, 1977; Punk concert poster. Xerox. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Stumblebunny, Max's Kansas City, 1977-08-31; Punk poster. Xerox. (Box 1, Folder 22)